<resources>
    <!--
      Copyright 2020 The Android Open Source Project
      Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
      in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
      Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the License
      is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express
      or implied. See the License for the specific language governing permissions and limitations under
      the License.
      -->
    <string name="app_name">ChooseAPuppy</string>
    <string name="welsh_corgi">Welsh Corgi</string>
    <string name="siberian_husky">Siberian Husky</string>
    <string name="dachshund">Dachshund</string>
    <string name="beagle">Beagle</string>
    <string name="rottweiller">Rottweiller</string>
    <string name="pug">Pug</string>
    <string name="akita_inu">Akita Inu</string>
    <string name="jack_russel_terrier">Jack Russel Terrier</string>
    <string name="pomeranian">Pomeranian</string>
    <string name="dalmatian">Dalmatian</string>
    <string name="chihuahua">Chihuahua</string>
    <string name="riesenschnauzer">Riesenschnauzer</string>
    <string name="shih_tzu">Shih Tzu</string>
    <string name="saint_bernard">Saint Bernard</string>
    <string name="doberman_pincher">Doberman Pincher</string>
    <string name="age_format">%d months</string>
    <string name="male">Male</string>
    <string name="female">Female</string>
    <string name="about_format">About %s</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>
    <string name="choose_a_puppy">Choose a puppy</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>


    <string name="welsh_corgi_description">
        The Welsh Corgi is a small type of herding dog that originated in Wales. Two separate breeds are recognised: the Pembroke Welsh Corgi and the Cardigan Welsh Corgi. There are physical differences between the two. According to the breed standards, overall the Cardigan is larger, both in weight and in height. Their tails are of different shapes; docking had previously been used. The Pembroke is the more popular of the two, yet still appears on The Kennel Club\'s Vulnerable dog breeds of the United Kingdom list. The Pembroke Welsh Corgi gained in popularity because the Queen has personally owned more than 30 Pembrokes or Corgi-Dachshund crosses, known as dorgis. Historically, the Pembroke has been attributed to the influx of dogs alongside Flemish weavers from around the 10th century, while the Cardigan is attributed to the dogs brought with Norse settlers, in particular a common ancestor of the Swedish Vallhund.
    </string>
    <string name="siberian_husky_description">
        The Siberian Husky is a medium-sized working sled dog breed. The breed belongs to the Spitz genetic family. It is recognizable by its thickly furred double coat, erect triangular ears, and distinctive markings, and is smaller than the similar-looking Alaskan Malamute. Siberian Huskies originated in Northeast Asia where they are bred by the Chukchi people of Siberia for sled-pulling, and companionship. It is an active, energetic, resilient breed, whose ancestors lived in the extremely cold and harsh environment of the Siberian Arctic. William Goosak, a Russian fur trader, introduced them to Nome, Alaska during the Nome Gold Rush, initially as sled dogs. Today, the Siberian Husky is typically kept as a house pet, though they are still frequently used as sled dogs by competitive and recreational mushers.
    </string>
    <string name="dachshund_description">$
    The dachshund, also known as the wiener dog, badger dog, or sausage dog, is a short-legged, long-bodied, hound-type dog breed. They may be smooth, wire, or long-haired. The standard sized dachshund was developed to scent, chase, and flush out badgers and other burrow-dwelling animals, while the miniature dachshund was bred to hunt small animals such as rabbits and mice. In the Western United States, they have also been used to track wounded deer and hunt prairie dogs. Dachshunds also participate in conformation shows, field trials and many other events organized through pure-bred dog organizations such as the American Kennel Club (AKC). According to the AKC, the dachshund is ranked 12th in popularity among dog breeds in the United States in 2018.
    </string>
    <string name="beagle_description">
        The beagle is a breed of small hound that is similar in appearance to the much larger foxhound. The beagle is a scent hound, developed primarily for hunting hare (beagling). Possessing a great sense of smell and superior tracking instincts, the beagle is the primary breed used as detection dogs for prohibited agricultural imports and foodstuffs in quarantine around the world. The beagle is intelligent. It is a popular pet due to its size, good temper, and a lack of inherited health problems. The modern breed was developed in Great Britain around the 1830s from several breeds, including the Talbot Hound, the North Country Beagle, the Southern Hound, and possibly the Harrier. Beagles have been depicted in popular culture since Elizabethan times in literature and paintings, and more recently in film, television, and comic books.
    </string>
    <string name="rottweiller_description">
        The Rottweiler is a breed of domestic dog, regarded as medium-to-large or large. The dogs were known in German as Rottweiler Metzgerhund, meaning Rottweil butchers\' dogs, because their main use was to herd livestock and pull carts laden with butchered meat to market. This continued until the mid-19th century when railways replaced droving. Although still used to herd stock in many parts of the world, Rottweilers are now also used as search and rescue dogs, guard dogs, and police dogs.
    </string>
    <string name="pug_description">
        The pug is a breed of dog with physically distinctive features of a wrinkly, short-muzzled face, and curled tail. The breed has a fine, glossy coat that comes in a variety of colours, most often light brown (fawn) or black, and a compact, square body with well-developed muscles. Pugs were brought from China to Europe in the sixteenth century and were popularized in Western Europe by the House of Orange of the Netherlands, and the House of Stuart. In the United Kingdom, in the nineteenth century, Queen Victoria developed a passion for pugs which she passed on to other members of the Royal family. Pugs are known for being sociable and gentle companion dogs. The American Kennel Club describes the breed\'s personality as "even-tempered and charming". Pugs remain popular into the twenty-first century, with some famous celebrity owners. A pug was judged Best in Show at the World Dog Show in 2004.</string>
    <string name="akita_inu_description">
The Akita is a large breed of dog originating from the mountainous regions of northern Japan. There are two separate varieties of Akita: a Japanese strain, commonly called Akita Inu (inu means dog in Japanese) or Japanese Akita, and an American strain, known as the Akita or American Akita. The Japanese strain comes in a narrow palette of colors, with all other colors considered atypical of the breed, while the American strain comes in all dog colors. The Akita has a short double-coat similar to that of many other northern spitz breeds such as the Siberian Husky, but long-coated dogs can also be found in many litters due to a recessive gene. The Akita is a powerful, independent and dominant breed, commonly aloof with strangers but affectionate with family members. As a breed, Akitas are generally hardy. In all countries except the United States, the Japanese and American strains of Akita are considered two separate breeds. In the United States, however, the two strains are considered a single breed with differences in type. For a while, the American strain of Akita was known in some countries as the Great Japanese Dog. Both forms of Akita are probably best known worldwide from the true story of Hachikō, a loyal Akita who lived in Japan before World War II.
    </string>
    <string name="jack_russel_terrier_description">
        The Jack Russell Terrier is a small terrier that has its origins in fox hunting in England. It is principally white-bodied and smooth, rough or broken-coated and can be any colour. Small tan and white terriers that technically belong to other breeds are sometimes known erroneously as \"Jack Russells\". Each breed has different physical characteristics according to the standards of their national breed clubs; size and proportions are often used to tell them apart. Some authorities recognize a similar but separate breed as the Russell Terrier – a shorter-legged, stockier dog, with a range of 20–30 cm (8–12 in). However, the Fédération Cynologique Internationale (FCI) regards the Russell terrier as a sub-type of Jack Russell terrier. Jack Russells are also frequently confused with the Parson Russell Terrier. Technically, the Parson Russell is usually larger and officially limited to a middle range, with a standard size of 30–36 cm (12–14 in), whereas the Jack Russell is a broader type, with a size range of 25–38 cm (10–15 in). Jack Russells are an energetic breed that rely on a high level of exercise and stimulation. They are relatively free from any serious health complaints. Originating from dogs bred and used by the Reverend John Russell in the early 19th century, from whom the breed takes its name, the Jack Russell has similar origins to the modern Fox Terrier. It has gone through several changes over the years, corresponding to different use and breed standards set by kennel clubs. Recognition by kennel clubs for the Jack Russell breed has been opposed by the breed\'s parent societies – which resulted in the breeding and recognition of the Parson Russell terrier. Jack Russells have appeared many times in film, television, and print – with several historical dogs of note.
    </string>
    <string name="pomeranian_description">
The Pomeranian (often known as a Pom) is a breed of dog of the Spitz type that is named for the Pomerania region in north-west Poland and north-east Germany in Central Europe. Classed as a toy dog breed because of its small size, the Pomeranian is descended from larger Spitz-type dogs, specifically the German Spitz. It has been determined by the Fédération Cynologique Internationale to be part of the German Spitz breed; and in many countries, they are known as the Zwergspitz ("Dwarf Spitz"). The breed has been made popular by a number of royal owners since the 18th century. Queen Victoria owned a particularly small Pomeranian and consequently, the smaller variety became universally popular. During Queen Victoria\'s lifetime alone, the size of the breed decreased by half. Overall, the Pomeranian is a sturdy, healthy dog. The most common health issues are luxating patella and tracheal collapse. More rarely, the breed can have Alopecia X, a skin condition colloquially known as "black skin disease". This is a genetic disease which causes the dog\'s skin to turn black and lose all or most of its hair. As of 2013, in terms of registration figures, since at least 1998, the breed has ranked among the top fifty most popular breeds in the United States, and the current fashion for small dogs has increased their popularity worldwide.
    </string>
    <string name="dalmatian_description">
        The Dalmatian is a breed of large-sized dog, noted for its unique white coat marked with black or liver-colored spots. Originating as a hunting dog, it was also used as a carriage dog in its early days. The origins of this breed can be traced back to Croatia and its historical region of Dalmatia. It is thought that early ancestors of the breed were certain breeds of pointers and a spotted Great Dane. Today, it is a popular family pet and many dog enthusiasts enter Dalmatians into kennel club competitions.
    </string>
    <string name="chihuahua_description">
        The Chihuahua is one of the smallest breeds of dog, and is named after the Mexican state of Chihuahua.
    </string>
    <string name="riesenschnauzer_description">
        The Giant Schnauzer is a breed of dog developed in the 17th century in Germany. It is the largest of the three breeds of Schnauzer—the other two breeds being the Standard Schnauzer and the Miniature Schnauzer. Numerous breeds were used in its development, including the black Great Dane, the Bouvier des Flandres, and the German Pinscher. Originally bred to assist on farms by driving livestock to market and guarding the farmer\'s property, the breed eventually moved into the city, where it worked guarding breweries, butchers\' shops, stockyards and factories. It was unknown outside of Bavaria until it became popular as a military dog during World War I and World War II. They have a dense coarse coat that protects them from the weather and from vermin. Giant Schnauzers come in two color patterns: Solid black, and a color known as pepper and salt, with banded hairs of alternating white and black, appearing gray at a distance. Where legal, they are shown with cropped ears and docked tails. Like other schnauzers, they have a distinct beard and eyebrows. Today, the Giant Schnauzer participates in numerous dog sports, including Schutzhund. Another sport that the dog excels in is that of nosework. Due to its alert nature, the dog is also used in police work.
    </string>
    <string name="shih_tzu_description">
        The Shih Tzu is a toy dog breed developed in Tibet.
    </string>
    <string name="saint_bernard_description">
        The St. Bernard or St Bernard is a breed of very large working dog from the western Alps in Italy and Switzerland. They were originally bred for rescue work by the hospice of the Great St Bernard Pass on the Italian-Swiss border. The hospice, built by and named after Italian monk Bernard of Menthon, acquired its first dogs between 1660 and 1670. The breed has become famous through tales of Alpine rescues, as well as for its large size.
    </string>
    <string name="doberman_pincher_description">The Dobermann, or Doberman Pinscher in the United States and Canada, is a medium-large breed of domestic dog that was originally developed around 1890 by Karl Friedrich Louis Dobermann, a tax collector from Germany. The Dobermann has a long muzzle. It stands on its pads and is not usually heavy-footed. Ideally, they have an even and graceful gait. Traditionally, the ears were cropped and posted and the tail was docked. However, in some countries, these procedures are now illegal. Dobermanns have markings on the chest, paws/legs, muzzle, above the eyes, and underneath the tail. Dobermanns are known to be intelligent, alert, and tenaciously loyal companions and guard dogs. Personality varies a great deal between each individual but, if taken care of and properly trained, they are generally considered to be loving and devoted companions. The Dobermann is driven, strong, and sometimes stubborn. With a consistent approach, they can be easy to train and will learn very quickly.</string>
    <string name="choose_a_dog">Choose a dog</string>

</resources>
